<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>The Word</title>
	<atom:link href="https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord</link>
	<description>The Word for all the World</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 04:23:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.13</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/cropped-TheWord-Icon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Word</title>
	<link>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>True Worship</title>
		<link>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/22/true-worship/</link>
		<comments>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/22/true-worship/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 17:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[nzimmer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/?p=86</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Worship is an action that many people do not understand the true power of. Jesus spoke to the women at the well in John 4. He told her that the time is coming and now is when]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Worship is an action that many people do not understand the true power of.  Jesus spoke to the women at the well in John 4.  He told her that the time is coming and now is when </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/22/true-worship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hindrances to Worship</title>
		<link>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/21/hindrances-to-worship/</link>
		<comments>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/21/hindrances-to-worship/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 16:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[nzimmer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[In Him]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/?p=66</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Worship is a key part of our relationship with God. David was called the man after God&#8217;s own heart because he delighted in worshiping God. And when he had removed [Saul], he raised up unto them David to be their king; to whom also he gave their testimony, and said, I have found David the&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Worship is a key part of our relationship with God.  David was called the man after God&#8217;s own heart because he delighted in worshiping God.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> And when he had removed [Saul], he raised up unto them David to be their king; to whom also he gave their testimony, and said, I have found David the son of Jesse, a man after mine own heart, which shall fulfill all my will. </p><cite>Acts 13:22 (KJV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>Worship allows us to get right into God&#8217;s face and tell Him we love Him.  Worship allows us to remind God of what His Word says and praise God for accomplishing it.  </p>



<p>But there are three things that stop believers from worshiping God.</p>



<ul><li>Pride</li><li>Fear</li><li>Shame</li></ul>



<p>These three things stop believers from being able to enter into God&#8217;s presence fully.  </p>



<h2>Pride</h2>



<p>Pride stops us from worshiping God.  Usually we see these people with their hands on the back of a chair or in their pockets looking down or around at others.  They care about how others see them more than God.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Though the&nbsp;Lord&nbsp;is great, he cares for the humble,&nbsp;but he keeps his distance from the proud. </p><cite>Psalm 138:6 (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>But as we see here this type of attitude stops us from getting close to God.  </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s put this where we understand.  Have you ever had that friend who is kind of the &#8220;uncool&#8221; person.  Maybe in high-school or college they were the one that everyone thought was kind of weird or different.  But you liked that person and wanted to hang out with them.  </p>



<p>How would that relationship go if you went to go talk to that uncool person and every time someone walked by you pretended you didn&#8217;t know them?  It wouldn&#8217;t be a relationship right? Because you could never get close for fear someone saw you with them.</p>



<p>This is the same way we treat God.  God is that friend that the world thinks is uncool.  It&#8217;s our pride that we let get in the way of our relationship with God.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Am I now trying to win the approval of human beings, or of God? Or am I trying to please people?&nbsp;If I were still trying to please people, I would not be a servant of Christ. </p><cite>Galatians 1:10 (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>We are going to see this scripture a lot because  a sold out God loving christian has to live by this thought.  You cannot let the approval of humans stop you from a relationship with God.  </p>



<h2>Fear</h2>



<p>Fear is another thing that stops us from worshiping God.  This goes right along with pride.  Fear of what others think or fear of how we will be treated stops us from worshiping God.  </p>



<p>Maybe we are afraid of what people will say about our voice, or we are afraid to raise our hands.  </p>



<p>Really it is a fear of commitment.  We are afraid to be sold out to God.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>And may your hearts&nbsp;be fully committed&nbsp;to the&nbsp;Lord&nbsp;our God, to live by his decrees and obey his commands, as at this time. </p><cite>1 Kings 8:61 (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>It comes back to Galatians 1:10.  It is a choice to put God first above what others think.  </p>



<p>You cannot let people dictate what you’re going to do.&nbsp; This applies not just to worship, but your whole life.&nbsp; Success in life is relative to the viewer.&nbsp; My version of success and your version of success look different because we have different goal, plans and visions for our lives.&nbsp; </p>



<p>Your success might look like $1 million and a huge corporation or it might look like 1 million souls saved and a small hut in Africa.&nbsp; And it would be what God wants either way.&nbsp; </p>



<p>BUT when you let someone else dictate your life.&nbsp; Your life starts to suffer because you
measure your success on someone else’s scale. </p>



<p>How does this apply to worship? It has everything to do with worship! You let someone else look at you singing or raising your hands and you let them tell you no.&nbsp; You let them tell you that getting close to God isn&#8217;t important.  </p>



<p>The sad thing is that most of the time they don’t even say anything.&nbsp; It’s the threat that someone might not agree that stops us.&nbsp; </p>



<h2>Guilt/Shame</h2>



<p>The final thing we let stop us from worshiping is guilt or shame.  We come into church and stand up ready to worship God and what happens?  Immediately we remember all the things we have done wrong last week or even in the last hour.  The fights we&#8217;ve had and the people we&#8217;ve talked bad about.  </p>



<p>What&#8217;s happening?  The devil is bringing back up all the reasons why you can&#8217;t worship.  But here&#8217;s a secret </p>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Your sin is not the Devil&#8217;s Business.</strong></p>



<p>When I first heard this I thought maybe the same thing you are.  How can sin not be the Devil&#8217;s business? Sin is like&#8230;HIS THING.  That&#8217;s what makes the Devil the Devil! </p>



<p>But the truth is that the devil is powerless since Jesus defeated him on the cross.  The Bible says </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> <br>Be&nbsp;sober, be&nbsp;vigilant;&nbsp;<sup>]</sup>because your adversary the devil walks about like a roaring lion, seeking whom he may devour. </p><cite>1 Peter 5:8 (NKJV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>At first glace you might say, &#8220;See! He is a lion powerful and able to devour me!&#8221; But look closer.  He walks about <em><strong>like</strong></em> a roaring lion.  He seeks who he <em><strong>may</strong></em> devour.  The devil is powerless until you give him power.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I give them eternal life,&nbsp;and they shall never perish;&nbsp;no one will snatch them out of my hand.&nbsp; My Father, who has given them to me,&nbsp;is greater than all;&nbsp;no one can snatch them out of my Father’s hand.&nbsp;<sup>&nbsp;</sup>I and the Father are one. </p><cite>John 10:28-30 (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>God has not come to condemn us but to bring us life and life more abundantly.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved. </p><cite>John 3:17 (KJV)</cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The thief does not come except to steal, and to kill, and to destroy. I have come that they may have life, and that they may have&nbsp;<em>it</em>&nbsp;more abundantly. </p><cite>John 10:10 (NKJV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>Because of salvation, we are free from condemnation of sin.  The devil and religion like to put us under condemnation, but God clearly says. . . </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>There is&nbsp;therefore now no condemnation to those who are in Christ Jesus,&nbsp;who do not walk according to the flesh, but according to the Spirit. </p><cite>Romans 8:1 (NKJV)<br></cite></blockquote>



<h2>Overcoming Pride, Fear and Shame</h2>



<p>So then how do we overcome these hindrances?  It comes back to James 4:7-8 and Psalm 138:3</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>So humble yourselves before God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.&nbsp;<sup>&nbsp;</sup>Come close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world. </p><cite>James 4:7-8 (NLT)</cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>In the day when I cried out, You answered me, And&nbsp;made me bold&nbsp;with&nbsp;strength in my soul. </p><cite>Psalm 138:3 (NKJV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>Here we see all three hindrances.  We start by humbling ourselves which gets rid of pride.  We resist the devil when he brings thoughts of unworthiness and shame.  Finally we press into worship ignoring fear as the spirit makes us bold to worship Him.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://thewordworld.github.io/TheWord/2019/01/21/hindrances-to-worship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
